Farewell, Earth
The ship that is departing is
The Space Battleship
Yamato
It departs now to Iscandar,
at the end of the cosmos,
bearing its fate.
"We will come back, no matter what it takes"
Answer with a smile to the waving people
Going far from the Galaxy towards Iscandar
A faint gleam of hope
The Space Battleship Yamato
<This is Recon Ship 13.>
<Yamato sighted.>
<Repeat...>
So we're restricted to visual range? They fought this way ages ago.
Captain!
Yeah, we'll go greet our guests.
Don't let them kill you... You kill them!
<Enemies overhead!>
<Incoming!>
Second Attack Force, launch immediately.
Repeat: Second Attack Force, launch immediately.
<Permission to launch.>
Fomt Berger, launching.
Second Attack Force is in position.
Activating Matter Transfer System!
Inputting recon data.
Coordinates: directly over the Yamato.
Preparing to fire matter transfer waves.
Fire!
There they are.
The enemy is right above us!
Direct hit!
Damage control!
Gunners, prepare for AA combat!
Maintain a wall of fire!
Secondary gunport 1 hit!
Damn it!
Bridge, this is Yamamoto.
Alpha 2, launching.
Melhi, you get the catapult.
I'll knock out its eyes.
We don't want it to sink yet.
Enemy to the rear!
I won't let you get away with this!
Port-side catapult has been destroyed!
Gunners, keep firing!
Yamato to fighters!
This is the Yamato! Do you read us?
We are under surprise attack!
All fighters are to return and defend the Yamato!
What?
These are decoys?!
Captain, what do we do?
Don't lose it, Kobashi!
I'll shoot them all down!
Daikuhara's down!
Akira, try to keep them busy!
One lone fighter held us all off?
Our job is done... Withdraw.
They're withdrawing.
Bridge Three to Bridge One.
The converter's damaged. We cannot deploy the Wave Motion Shields.
At this rate, it will affect our inertial control!
I'll head up the repairs.
But where did they come from?
Warp.
That's impossible... Warping in those little fighters?
You can't fight if you only rely on what you think you know.
The enemy commander is excellent.
Excellent, Berger.
Surface, then release our guest.
Be certain you remember this face.
She's beautiful...
She is of noble birth.
Don't fall in love, Norran.
Huh? N-No way...
Norran, stay here and secure the airlock.
Zar Belk.
Well, Barlen? How does it feel, being back in that old bucket?
Wonderful... I may look old, but I'm as sharp as I was in my youth.
Garlent, taking off!
The enemy commander has more in store.
Keep an eye on the surroundings, everyone.
With our own eyes?
With our ship blinded and deafened,
victory depends on our own human ability.
There should be a current of ion turbulence nearby.
Use the data we've gathered to find it.
Yes, sir.
Enemy dead ahead!
I have a present for you!
A dud?
Present delivered.
I'm pulling out...
I won't let you escape!
Okay! Everyone to stations!
Right!
Yurisha!
Hoshina...
We don't know where the enemy will come from!
It's dangerous here.
Listen! Use your eyes to find them!
Please keep back.
Keep back...
What is that?
Sending data on dud to Bridge Three.
Wave Motion Gun Control Room, report.
Enemy device advancing toward the gun's chamber!
Pressure in chamber is dropping!
Close the safety valves! Now!
Watch out!
Hurry!
Get out of here! Go!
Inertial control is down.
So that was no dud.
It probably had a delay fuse.
This is a problem...
This is Sanada, on Bridge Three.
Hmm? What is it?
I have a suggestion.
You there...
I don't think I've seen you before. Where are you stationed?
We are...
Someone's fired a gun on deck 6!
It was a Garmillan gun!
Security to deck 6. Kodai, take command.
Yes, sir.
Hoshina!
No!
They've seen our faces.
What are you doing?
The Iscandarian!
Excuse me.
We have her.
Anabiosis Performed Successfully
I'm surprised it got through so easily.
It wasn't a weapon to begin with.
They turned it into a makeshift weapon. That's probably why.
A logical conclusion.
<Initiating connection.>
The enemy is starting to get cornered.
So are we, I guess.
N-No!
You okay, rookie?
Sawamura.
Don't push yourself.
Enemy ship at ten o'clock!
That's a carrier.
Kobashi, wait!
I'll do this!
Kobashi! Kobashi!
I'm no coward!
Enemy to port side!
Begin AA fire!
Mother!
Kobashi!
Damn it!
Not bad...
<You are skilled.>
<However...>
<This is the end.>
<Rear Brigadier Ghetto!>
<The Balgrey has been sunk! >
<What?!>
<Damn!>
You're mine!
<Ghale Domel!>
We'll help you.
Garmillan soldiers?
Mori!
Go on ahead!
Right!
Bridge, Garmillans are on board!
Captain! Damn it!
Captain!
Captain Gelt!
Go, Norran... Go!
Fulfill your mission, and make Zaltz proud!
Hail Zaltz!
Yuki!
Yuki! Yuki!
Surface.
Prepare to retrieve the suckerfish.
What do I do? What do I do?
Yuki!
Encrypted message from the Hound.
The suckerfish has our target.
The Schderg is requesting permission to launch the attack teams.
Do we send them?
Once the boring projectile explodes, it should finish the Yamato.
But there are no certainties in battle.
Launch the torpedo bombers and ensure that we sink the Yamato.
Third Attack Force, launch!
Niimi to bridge. The detonator has been disabled.
Excellent.
Well done.
Good job.
Die, Garmillans!
Damn it, I won't let you get away with this!
Third Attack Force here! Requesting reinforcements!
We have encountered and engaged the enemy!
Die!
Sir!
So the heavens tell me to sink the Yamato myself?
Then I shall do their bidding.
Fleet, advance!
We're mooring you.
Fighters have returned.
Twelve didn't make it back...
Resupply as fast as you can.
Ota, did you find that ion turbulence?
Y-Yes.
Recon Team to bridge!
Enemy ships to starboard!
So they're here.
Analyzer!
Go.
<Reverse.>
<Connected.>
Evasive maneuvers!
Turn forty degrees to port! Combat speed 1!
But the ion storm is right there! If it sucks us in, we'll be adrift!
Did you not hear my order?
Yes, sir!
Changing course. Forty degrees to port.
Ota, transmit the enemy device's course to the gunnery officer.
Nanbu, when its axis is aligned with the enemy fleet, shoot it.
Yes, sir.
Don't miss, sir.
Leave it to me. Guns are my specialty.
Evasive maneuvers!
The Schderg is down!
Remain calm!
Enemy ship is firing!
Damn it! I'll load missiles and launch.
Don't be stupid!
I want revenge...
I refuse to let it end this way!
Berger!
Fire all cannons!
Fire!
Keep calm! Fire!
Concentrate all remaining firepower on that ship!
Keep firing at them!
What?
Right the ship!
We can't! The ion turbulence has us!
Was this their plan?
The ion turbulence has caught the enemy ship!
Did they lure me here?
My arrogance led me to try to sink them personally...
At the very end, I made the wrong move.
Engine output is dropping!
Turn to port!
The helm's not responding! We can't maintain the ship!
Elk Domel, ID #17492-ZEKU.
Sir, that's...
This is now my personal fight.
All crew, abandon ship!
Looks like we're all headed to the
court martial for disobeying orders.
Prepare to fire anchor!
This looks bad.
Just a little more.
The enemy has attached itself to the bottom of the ship.
Enemy ship is hailing us.
Video message.
Display it.
I wish to speak to your commander.
I am this ship's captain, Juzo Okita.
I am Garmillas Military Galactic Theater Commander Elk Domel.
At last, we meet.
I share your sentiment.
Captain Okita, allow me to express my
admiration for your splendid command.
Commander Domel, the battle is over.
I do not wish to fight if it isn't necessary.
Will you let us pass?
I cannot do that.
If you are a soldier, you should understand.
If I allow the Yamato to pass, my men will have died in vain.
Captain Okita, as a soldier... No, as a man,
I am proud to have met a man like you before my death.
Blessings and honor to you Terrons and to those of us from Garmillas!
The enemy is going to self-destruct!
All crew on the lower decks, evacuate!
Elk...
Did we make it?
That was close...
The Wave Motion Shield came on line in time.
Yes.
Divert power to the engines. We're leaving this area.
Are you...
Are you Yuki?
No.
I am not Yuki.
I am Yurisha Iscandar.
Episode 20
Under a Rainbow Sun
Among the distant stars
Can you hear the wandering souls?
In this galaxy, they can forever rest in peace
Requiem of separation
With this requiem
Sing Along!
Voices sing to praise
An unforgettable memory
And we’ll never forget your name
Farewell friend,
my sorrow
Will not run out
Someday in this sea of stars
Surely
Pray for the Earth!
The oath
Pray for the dream!
The ideal
Last forever!
A requiem sounds in the sky.
The Yamato barely survives its battle with Domel,
and heads to a new planet to recover from its wounds.
It is Leptapoda, a desert planet.
And it holds another side as well...
Next time: Prison Planet 17.
There are 230 days left before humanity is extinct.